Guide to the Barbara Pryor Collection of Northern Ireland Ephemera and Publications AIA.091
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Barbara Pryor Collection of Northern Ireland Ephemera and Publications
1922-1999
1970s-1990s
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Pryor, Barbara
AIA.091
4.25 linear feet in 6 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, and 1 flat box
Barbara Pryor is a former member of the Belfast H-Block Committee, and helped produce publications advocating for the rights of political prisoners in Northern Ireland in the early 1980s. The Barbara Pryor Collection of Northern Ireland Ephemera and Publications (dated 1922-1999) consists of ephemera and publications collected by Pryor documenting her engagement with social movements and political action in Northern Ireland in the late 20th century. Major topics include Irish republicanism, anti-British imperialism, socialism, feminism, prisoners' rights, and anti-nuclear activism. The majority of the materials in this collection document activities in or near Belfast, but also include materials produced in Ireland and the United States. The 1981 hunger strikes by Irish republican prisoners in the H-Blocks of Long Kesh prison and the Armagh Women's Prison are heavily documented. The collection demonstrates varied viewpoints of republican activism, including physical force republicanism, nonviolent advocacy, and legislative compromise.
Scope and Contents
The Barbara Pryor Collection of Northern Ireland Ephemera and Publications (dated 1922-1999) consists of ephemera and publications collected by Pryor documenting her engagement with social movements and political action in Northern Ireland in the late 20th century. Major topics include Irish republicanism, anti-British imperialism, socialism, feminism, prisoners' rights, and anti-nuclear activism. The majority of the materials in this collection document activities in or near Belfast, but also include materials produced in Ireland and the United States. The 1981 hunger strikes by Irish republican prisoners in the H-Blocks of Long Kesh prison and the Armagh Women's Prison are heavily documented. The collection demonstrates varied viewpoints of republican activism, including physical force republicanism, nonviolent advocacy, and legislative compromise.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Barbara Pryor in October 2021; the accession number associated with this gift is 2023.102.
Appraisal
Publications already represented in the Tamiment Library collections were appraised out of the collection and returned to the donor.
Biographical Note
Barbara Pryor is a former member of the Belfast H-Block Committee, and helped produce publications advocating for the rights of political prisoners in Northern Ireland in the early 1980s.
Fliers (printed matter); Pamphlets.; Hunger strikes -- Northern Ireland.; Human rights -- Northern Ireland.; Political prisoners -- Ireland.; Nuclear disarmament.; Nuclear energy.; Peace movements -- Northern Ireland; Northern Ireland -- History -- 1968-1998; Social movements -- Northern Ireland; Pryor, Barbara
- British Strategy In Northern Ireland: From The White Paper In The Fall Of Sunningdale; Published by IMG, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Burntollet; Published by Bowes Egan and Vincent McCormack, October 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Censoring "The Troubles": An Irish Solution To An Irish Problem?; Published by IFJ Fact-finding Mission to Ireland, January 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Civil Rights Guardian; Published by Organ of the Irish Civil Rights Action League, circa 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Class Struggle: The Lessons Of Chile; Published by Irish Workers Group, October 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Combat: The Journal Of The Ulster Volunteers, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Common Ground Pat Finucane Centre'S Quarterly Newsletter, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Fortnight: An Independent Review For Northern Ireland, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- A Belfast Directory: The Other Yellow Pages; Published by Just Books, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- A Comprehensive Guide To Information On Ireland; Published by Troops Out Turf, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- A Far Far Better Way:Discussion Document; Published by Cooperation North, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- A Resources Guide To The North Of Ireland; Published by Information on Ireland, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Abortion And The Catholic Church: Two Feminists Defend Women'S Rights, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Constitution Of The Free State Of Ireland (English Translation), 1922 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Factsheets On Britain And Europe, July 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Constitution Of Ireland, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Danny Barrett: A British Army Murder; Published by Fr. Faul and Fr Murray, January 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Economic And Social Policy 1982 Aims And Recommendations; Published by National Economic and Social Council, February 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Erin's Hope: The End And The Means:The New Evangel; Published by James Connolly, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Eire Nua: A New Democracy; Published by Republican Sinn Fein, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- For A Revolutionary Party; Published by Bob Pennington, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Framed Through The Special Criminal Court: The Great Train Robbery Trial,; Published by Starry Plough, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- H-Block And Its Background; Published by Fr. Faul and Fr. Murray, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Hunger Strike Settlement; Published by Irish Northern Aid: Irish Prisoners of War Committee, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- H-Block- The British Government's Treatment Of Irish Political Prisoners; Published by Irish Northern Aid, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Hunger Strike H-Blocks, Long Kesh, Northern Ireland 27; Published by Lawyers and Priests for A Humanitarian Alternative, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Hunger Strikes- The Search For Solutions; Published by Fr. Faul and Fr. Murray, May 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Liberal Focus: An Ulster Liberal Publication; Published by Ulster Liberal Party, Summer 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Magill, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- No Hanging Here: The Case Of Marie And Noel Murray,; Published by Murray Defense Committee, circa 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Northern Ireland Constitution Act 1973. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Magill: Book Of Irish Politics, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Toward Human Rights And Truth Recovery: Pat Finucane Center Newsletter; Published by The Pat Finucane Center, 2011-2015 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Michael Mccartan: An Innocent Catholic Boy Shot Dead By The Ruc 23 July 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Just News: Bulletin Of The Committee On The Administration Of Justice; Published by Committee on the Administration of Justice, October 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- New Ireland Forum Report of Proceedings, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Guth An Phobail Reports From Occupied Ireland, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- All Clear: The Newsheet Of Coleraine Anti-Nuke/C.N.D. Group, circa 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Crisis In The Gulf; Published by Institute for Policy Studies, October 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Undercurrents: Environment Special Free Festival Guide, June/July 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- No No Nato; Published by John Cox, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- No Nukes Left!, A Political Newsjournal For The Anti-Nuclear Movement, Summer 1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- No Parking Reserved For Cruise Missiles, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Nuclear Ireland?; Published by Matthew Hussey and Carole Craig, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Nuclear Power And Ireland; Published by Research Section Department of Economic Affairs Sinn Fein The Workers' Party, circa 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Nuclear The Impossible Gamble; Published by Revolutionary Struggle, June 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Scram Energy Bulletin, June/July 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Snuff Out The Stench Of Nuclear War; Published by Peace and Detente Association, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- War Lords, Cis Report The Uk Arms Industry, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Wise: World Information Service On Energy: International Networking Bulletin For The Safe Energy Movement, September 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Pershing Ii And Cruise Missles Spreading Chaos; Published by Clergy and Laity Concerned, circa 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- The Nuclear North Atlantic; Published by Olafur Grimsson and Angus McCormack, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Namebase Newsline; Published by Steve Badrich, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- The Lobster; Published by Voice Unit 51, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Outta Control:Belfast Anarchist Monthly, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Nuclear War: The Facts You Should Know And What You Can Do To Help Prevent It; Ecoropa Information Sheet 5., undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Peace Moves Nuclear Protest In The 1980s; Published by Ed Barber, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Poland: Workers In Revolt; Published by Dave Frankel, DeAnn Rathbun, and Ernest Harsch, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- A Dossier Concerning Treatment Of Prisoners During And After A Disturbance At Albany Prison In September 1976",; Published by Amnesty International (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Disarmament Today, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Toxic Times; Published by Finglas Toxic Action Group, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Nuclear Times; Published by Nuclear Times, October 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- "No-U-Turn: Report On Uranium Mining In France"; Published by Collectif Autonome d' Intervention et de Mobilisation Anti-Nucleaire, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- "Nuclear Weapons And Nuclear Power"; Published by SCRAM Energy Bulletin, June 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Dawn An Irish Journal Of Nonviolence, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Suffer The Children:Chemical Threats To Fertility; Published by The Contaminated Crow, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- The Case Against Carnsore: Nuclear Power, Economics And Sovereignty"; Published by Communist Party of Ireland, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- End Journal Pullout; Published by Pullout, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Nuclear Times: A Newsmagazine On The Anti-Nuclear Weapons Movement; Published by Nuclear Times, January 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- The Windscale Threat"; Published by News Line, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Toxic Ireland; Published by Alliance for Safety and Health, February 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Uranium Exploration Ins Ulster-The Multinational Menace"; Published by Just Books, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- We Don't Want A War No To NATO Now; Published by Campaign for Nuclear Disarmament, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Against Violence In Ireland,; Published by Desmond Wilson, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- America 200Th Anniversary; Published by IRSP Collective in Cage 14 (Long Kesh), September 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- American Irish Newsletter; Published by American Irish Political Education Committee, 1983-1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- An Irish Tragedy: Britain's Disgrace: Another Irish Child Killed By A British Plastic Bullet; Published by Information on Ireland, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Anglo-Irish Agreement, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Apartheid In Britain-An Analysis Of The Prevention Of Terrorism Act, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Northern Ireland: A History Of Repression; Published by Chartist Publication, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Northern Ireland (Emergency Provisions) Act 1973., 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Northern Ireland Human Rights Review; Published by American Protestants for Truth About Ireland, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Human Rights Watch Report: "Northern Ireland: The Murder Of Rosemary Nelson"; Published by Human Rights Watch, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Uranium Mining In Donegal: The Dangers And Deceits"; Published by Just Books, November 1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- "Uranium: The Threat To Leinster; Published by The Contaminate Crow, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Women's Action; Published by Women's Action Belfast Women's Collective, May/June 1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Bernadette Devlin Mcaliskey On The Irish Freedom Struggle; Published by Pathfinder Press, March 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Beyond The Religious Divide; Published by New Ulster Political Research Group, March 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Birmingham Six Committee Newsletter, March 1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Breaking The Deadlock: A Way Out Of The Northern Impasse; Published by Robert Heatley, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- British Army Terror West Belfast; Published by Fr. Brady, Faul and Murray, September October 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- British Labor And Ireland: 1969: The Cost Of Bipartisanship: The Case For Troops Out Now; Published by Geoff Bell, August 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- British Soldiers Speak Out On Ireland 1969-1979, 1968-1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Northern Ireland News Service, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Northern Ireland Report, November 1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Northern Irish Stereotypes; Published by E.E. O'Donnell, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Our Own Red Blood: The Story Of The 1916 Rising; Published by Sean Cronin, August 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Out! Report From The National Labour Movement Delegation To Ireland Summer, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Belfast Community Economic Conference; Published by Island 12 Pamphlets, June 1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Iris: The Republican Magazine, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- No British Solution; Published by Troops Out Movement, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- The Irish Left For Revolutionary Regroupment; Published by Independent Socialist Party, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- The Way Forward: Address By Gerry Adams Of the National H-Block-Armagh National Committee, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- West Belfast: Some Of The Facts Behind The Issues; Published by Falls Community Council, 1987-11-01T00:00:00+00:00 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- A Miscarriage Of Justice; Published by Committee on the Administration of Justice, circa 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Ad Hoc Committee To Support Irish Political Prisoners, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Nicky Kelly News, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Outta Control:Belfast Anarchist Monthly, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Socialist Republic, 1968, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- "What You Can Do To Prevent Nuclear War"; Published by Irish Campaign for Nuclear Disarmament, August 1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- "Women And Nukes", undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Hard Luck Hard Rock; Published by Campaign for Nuclear Disarmament, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Uranium Grabber; Published by Cork City Anti-Nuke Group, June 1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Camera Work; Published by Half Moon Photography Workshop, March 1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Dawn An Irish Magazine On Nonviolent Action Civil Liberties And Movements For Change, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Disarm, Ireland's Anti-Nuclear Magazine, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Red Herring, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Region I: Civil Defence And Nuclear War In The North East; Published by Martin Spence, January 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Resist Nuclear Power; Published by Anarchists in Ireland, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Sanity; Published by CND Publications, August 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- The Contaminated Crow, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- The Radioactive Times: The Journal Of The Belfast Cnd Group,; Published by Belfast CND Group, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- The Lobster; Published by Voice Unit 51, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Belfast Bulletin; Published by Belfast Workers Research Unit, 1977-1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Belafast Workers Reasearch Bulletin: Women In Ireland, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Belfast Bulletin; Published by Belfast Workers Research Unit, 1977-1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- The Irish Civil War 1922-1923: And What It Still Means For The Irish People; Published by Frances M. Blake, West London United Troops Our Movement, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
- The Queen Comes To Belfast; Published by Workers Research Unit, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Trade Unions And H Block A Background To The Protest, Criminalization Policy, And Conveyor Belt Process Leading To The H Blocks Of Long Kesh; Published by Trade Union Sub-Committee of the National H Blocks Committee, circa 1980 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Troops Out Paper Of The United Troops Out Movement, 1977-1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Women Protests For Political Status In Armagh Gaol; Published by Report by Women Against Imperialism, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Women's News, Oct/Nov 1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- The Way Forward, National Economic Plan 1983-1987; Published by Government of Ireland, October 1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- The Voice Of Ulster: The Official Journal Of The Ulster Democratic Unionist Party, August 1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- The Work Of Justice: Pastoral Letter Of The Irish Bishops, circa 1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- They Shoot Children: The Use Of Rubber And Plastic Bullets In The North Of Ireland, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- United Kingdom: Northern Ireland: Killings By "Supergrass" Trials; Published by Amnesty International, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Voice Of The Innocent, 7 Young Men From Ballymurphy, Belfast Arrested And Tortured, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Violations Of Human Rights In Northern Ireland 1968-1978; Published by Fr. Faul and Fr. Murray, circa 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- State Research, News And Developments, June-July 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- The Irish Industrial Revolution; Published by Sinn Fein The Workers' Party, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- The Ripening Of Time:The Agony Of A Dream, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- The Stripping Naked Of The Women Prisoners In Armagh Prison, 1982-83; Published by Fr. Denis Faul, Easter 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Strip Searching: An Inquiry Into The Strip Searching Of Women Remand Prisoners At Armagh Prison Between 1982 And 1985, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Stop Strip-Searches, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Stop Strip Searching, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Sunday Bloody Sunday; Published by Starry Plough Publications, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- The Teachings Of James Connolly; Published by Joseph Deasy, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- The United Kingdom In 1980: The Hudson Report, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- The Captive Voice, The Voice Of Irish Republican Prisoners Of War, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- The Irish Prisoner; Published by Prisoners Aid Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
- The Misrule Of Law:A Report On The Policing Of Events During The Summer Of 1996 In Northern Ireland; Published by Committee on the Administration of Justice, October 1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- The New Labour And Ireland, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- The Phoenix, August 1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- The Irish Republican Congress; Published by George Gilmore, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- The Prevention Of Terrorism Acts 1974 And 1976: A Report On The Operation Of The Law,; Published by Catherine Scorer (Box 5, Folder 2)
- The Re-Conquest Of Ireland By James Connolly; Published by James Connolly, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- The Relevance Of James Connolly In Ireland Today; Published by George Gilmore, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Report Of A Committee To Consider, In The Context Of Civil Liberities And Human Rights Measures To Deal With Terrorism In Northern Ireland; Published by Lord Gardiner, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Statement On Defence Estimates, 1977: Presented To Parliament By The Secretary Of State For Defence By Command Of Her Majesty; Published by Her Majesty's Stationery Office (Box 5, Folder 2)
- The Public Sector And The Profit Makers; Published by Studies in Political Economy, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Saoirse, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Soldier Of Fortune :War Around The World: Lebanon, Afghanistan, British Sbs/Sas In The Falklands, December 1982 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- War In Peace; Published by Orbis Publication, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Report Of The Committee Of Privy Counsellors Appointed To Consider Authorised Procedures For The Interrogation Of Persons Suspected Of Terrorism,; Published by Lord Parker, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Report Of The Commission To Consider Legal Procedures To Deal With Terrorist Activities In Northern Ireland, (Diplock Report), 1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Report Of The Enquiry Into Allegations Against The Security Forces Of Physical Brutaity In Northern Ireland Arising Out Of Events On The 9Th August, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Report Of The Tribunal Appointed To Inquire Into The Events On Sunday, 30Th January 1972, Which Led To Loss Of Life In Connection With The Procession In London On The Day (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Rosemary Nelson: The Life And Death Of A Human Rights Defender; Published by Pat Finucane Center, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Scarlet Women Ii, Newsletter Of The Socialist Feminist Current Of The Women'S Liberation Movement, June 1980 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Searchlight: The Anti-Fascist Monthly; Ulster: New Evidence Of Nazi Loyalist Links, August 1982 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Peoples' News Service, February 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Amnesty International Newsletter, April 1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Policies For Industrial Development:Conclusions And Recommendations; Published by National Economic and Social Council, September 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Statuary Instruments: Prevention Of Terrorism 1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Prison Struggle, Paper Of The Relatives Action Committee, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Prisoners Of Partition: H-Block/Armagh; Published by Peoples Democracy, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Prisoners Of War In The Fight For Irish Freedom, 3/1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Problems Of The Irish Revolution: Can The Ira Meet The Challenge; Published by Gerry Foley, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Sinn Fein Foreign Affairs Bureau Information Service: Programmes On The North Of Ireland: Banned, Censored Or Delayed 1959-1986; Published by Sinn Fein Foreign Affaires Bureau, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- An Camcheachta The Starry Plough; Published by Irish Republican Socialist Party, circa 1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Report Of The Afl-Cio Delegation To Northern Ireland And To The Republic Of Ireland; Afl-Cio, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Report Of An Amnesty International Mission To Northern Ireland, November 28 To December 1977; Published by Amnesty International, June 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- The European Monetary System; Published by, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- The H Blocks: An Indictment Of British Prison Policy In The North Of Ireland; Published by Information on Ireland, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Private Eye; Published by Pressdram Ltd, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Supergrasses: The Use Of Accomplice Evidence In Northern Ireland; Published by Tony Gifford QC, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- The Agreement, Agreement Between The Government Of The United Kingdom And Great Britain And Northern Ireland And The Government Of Ireland, April 1998 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- The American Gael, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- The Best Documented Killing: Report Of A Public Inquiry Into Events Of August 12, 1984 At Anderstown, Belfast; Published by Springhill Community House, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Sgoil Eanna, St. Edna's School, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Socialism Made Easy, James Connolly; Published by The Plough Book Service, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Songs Of Rsistance 1968-1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- The British Media And Ireland: Truth The First Casualty, The Campaign For Free Speech On Ireland, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- The Irish Free State And British Imperialism; Published by "Gerhard", Cork Workers Club, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Tony O'Reilly's Last Game: A Case History Of Irish Capitalism; Published by Sinn Fein, The Workers Party, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Tory Island: A Case Of Deliberate Neglect, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Understanding And Co-Operation In Ireland: Republic Of Ireland And Northern Ireland Trade In Manufactured Goods, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Who Owns Ireland Who Owns You; Published by Attic Press, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Peace And Reconciliation Projects In Ireland, A Directory By Ian M. Ellis, April 1983 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Peace In Ireland; A Broad Analysis Of The Present Situation; Published by Gerry Adams, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)